# **Shagun Sharma**

🗣 India 🗷 sharmashagun426@gmail.com 🛘 (+91)9996632053 🚡 https://www.linkedin.com/in/shagun-vashisth-7b93b317b/ https://shagun.onrender.com

#### **SUMMARY**

Meticulous Software Engineer with 4+ years of experience Team Leading and designing and developing of software and project management solutions. In-depth understanding of web technologies with focus on delivering innovative business solutions. Excels in fast-paced, highenergy and deadline-driven environment with willingness to take on additional tasks.

# **EXPERIENCE**

## Senior ReactJs Developer Bada Business Pvt. Ltd.

November 2023 - Present, New Delhi, India

- · Developed and designed modular UI components and Dashboards using latest React.JS, isomorphic JavaScript, Redux and various open source libraries to create optimized, bug-free applications.
- · Reduced development effort and timelines by 15% by improving reusability of code with new React component libraries and techniques.
- · Utilized React-testing-library to unit test components and created various prototypes to quickly build applications, relying on information gathered from the product team.

# Software Engineer (ReactJs, Elixir, PHP) Chetu India Pvt Ltd.

June 2021 - September 2022, Noida, India

- · Developed and maintained multiple applications with an agile methodology, including developing microservices, unit tests, and UI components.
- · Increased throughput and responsiveness of System by 25%, and reduced response time by 10%, and implemented robust and optimized error-handling protocols.
- · Worked with backend developers to implement prototype elements into web applications. Attended scrum meetings and attended the client call weekly and present the live demonstration to stakeholder.

## Web Developer(PHP, WordPress, JavaScript) VisiWeb Solutions Pvt Ltd

December 2019 - June 2020, Noida, India

- · Developed, tested, and maintained web applications using PHP, WordPress, JavaScript, HTML/CSS, and API integration.
- · Achieved 89% issue resolution rate within the allotted timeline, improving user experience by 3x and increasing customer engagement by
- · Designed websites, portals and large-scale web applications for multiple clients. Built layouts according to customer parameters using HTML and CSS3, Bootstrap 4, ReactJs, PHP.
- · Developed web-based PHP and ReactJS applications for deployment on premiums service platforms.

# FullStack Web Developer (PHP, JavaScript)

SachTech Solutions Pvt. Ltd.

June 2019 - November 2019, Mohali, India

- · Developed and implemented a robust back-end platform using PHP resulting in an increase in website loading speed by 23% while reducing the number of errors and bugs.
- · Developed an e-commerce system utilizing JavaScript, HTML, CSS and PHP, increasing usability and customer satisfaction by 27%.
- · Collaborated with web developer to accept assignments and support administrative tasks for development.

## **PROJECTS**

#### Novuskin Med Spa

- · Description: At Novuskin, we're a unique aesthetic treatment center that believes no matter where you're at in your skincare journey, you're beautiful, just the way you are. Taking care of your skin is about so much more than just how you look. Skincare is skin health. When our skin is healthy, we feel more confident and powerful.
- Technologies Used: List the technologies, tools, and frameworks utilized in application, ReactJS, Redux, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap-4.
- · Responsibilities: As a frontend developer, I have likely created a dashboard that serves as a central hub for displaying various data and insights related to sales, leads, revenue, spend, and other relevant metrics. I have designed reusable components to ensure consistency and modularity within the dashboard, making it easier to maintain and expand the functionality.
- · Dashboard and Reusable Components:
- · Graph and Chart Implementation
- · Data Export in CSV Format
- · RESTful API
- · JWT Token-Based Authentication

# **Apprent**

- · Apprent is a multifamily maintenance software for property managers, leadership, technicians, and residents.
- · As a Fullstack developer, I have likely add new functionality and implement 3rd parties property solutions that serves as a central hub for displaying various data and insights.
- · Implement third party property management RESTfull API and web-hooks for get data from third party application.

#### **Performance Dashboard**

Bada Business Pvt Ltd · https://performance.badabusiness.com/ · November 2022 - Present

• Performance Dashboard gives you visibility into the performance of the entire partners network, as well as to the performance of your passive revenue and more data about the partner in order of graphically and numerically.

## **EDUCATION**

### **Bachelor of Technology in CSE**

Shri Venkateshwara University · Gajraula, Uttar Pradesh, India · 2023

# **Diploma In Computer Science and Engineering**

CDL Government Polytechnic College · Sirsa, Haryana, India · 2019

# **CERTIFICATIONS**

# Certified Business Intelligence using Tableau

Great Learning · 2021

Business Intelligence (BI) using Tableau refers to the process of leveraging Tableau software to analyze, visualize, and gain insights from data to make data-driven decisions.

#### Google Digital Unlocked

Google · 2019

The program offers a variety of online courses and tutorials covering various aspects of digital marketing, including search engine optimization (SEO), search advertising, content marketing, social media marketing, email marketing, analytics, and more. The content is designed to be beginner–friendly, making it accessible to individuals with little to no prior experience in digital marketing.

# **PHP Developer**

SachTech Solutions Pvt Ltd · 2018

Certified PHP & WordPress Developer with Javascript and HTML and CSS

# **SKILLS**

ReactJs, Redux, TypeScript, JavaScript, PHP, JQuery, Elixir, Github/SVN, Ubuntu/Window, MySQL, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, HTML, CSS, Tailwind CSS, Bootstrap-4, WordPress, MUI